<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
    <category>
        <pattern>JOBCHAT</pattern>
        <template>
            Okay. Are there any careers you're already familiar with or interested in?
            <think><set name="topic">cscareers</set></think>
        </template>
    </category>
	<!-- Categories governing discussion on potential careers in computer science. -->
	<topic name="cscareers">
	    <!-- Offering guidance based on no pre-existing preference or knowledge. -->
	    <category>
	        <pattern>NO</pattern>
	        <template>
	            That's alright. There's such a wide variety of exciting and
	            lucrative opportunities in CS. Which is great, but can make
	            finding where to start a little intimidating! No worries.
	            Tell me a bit about what you're looking for in a job.
	        </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ SOFTWARE *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template>
                Ahhh, a very common choice, but rightly so, and there's so much
                variety within the profession!
                <br/>
                If you'd like the opportunity to solve real world problems through
                designing software based solutions that implement the principles
                you're learning in your CS degree, you should read into Software
                Engineering and Development.
                <br/>
                <link>
                    <text>Here's some more info to get you started</text>
                    <url>https://www.onetonline.org/link/summary/15-1252.00</url>
                </link>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ PROFESSORING *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template><srai>I WANT A JOB WHERE TEACHING IS INVOLVED</srai></template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ TEACHING *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template>
                If you're after a career in teaching, read up on being a
                Computer Science Professor!
                <link>
                    <text>Check out some more in depth info here.</text>
                    <url>https://www.onetonline.org/link/summary/25-1021.00</url>
                </link>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ RESEARCH *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template>
                If you're interested in applying analysis and reasoning to
                develop new computer technologies and devise solutions to both
                abstract and functional problems in CS, maybe you should look
                into being a Computer Scientist Researcher or Development Scientist!
                <link>
                    <text>Learn more about being a computer pioneer here!</text>
                    <url>https://www.onetonline.org/link/summary/15-1221.00</url>
                </link>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ ADMINISTRATION *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template>
                If the idea of designing, securing, and maintaining computers
                at both an individual and large-scale level appeals to you, 
                you're in luck! Companies are always hiring System Admins, 
                Network Architects, IT Security personnel, and more...
                <link>
                    <text>
                        Learn more about these and similar jobs here.
                    </text>
                    <url>https://www.onetonline.org/link/summary/15-1244.00</url>
                </link>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>_ DATA SCIENCE *</pattern>
            <that>TELL ME A BIT ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR IN A JOB</that>
            <template>
                For those of us with a love for statistics and raw data, just
                begging to be sorted and analyzed, a job as a data scientist might
                be just what the doctor ordered!
                <link>
                    <text>Learn more about jobs in data science here.</text>
                    <url>https://www.onetonline.org/link/summary/15-2051.00</url>
                </link>
            </template>
        </category>

        <!-- Similar guidance for students who already have some knowledge of
             on or more cs careers. -->
        <category>
            <pattern>YES</pattern>
            <template>
                Oh, good! What career are you interested in then?
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>I AM INTERESTED IN <set>careers</set></pattern>
            <template>
                I see. That sounds like an excellent choice. But does that career, 
                or other like it in CS suit your expectations, I wonder? Tell me a bit
                about what you're looking for in a job.
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern><set>careers</set></pattern>
            <template><srai>I AM INTERESTED IN <star/></srai></template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>I AM INTERESTED IN *</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry - I haven't been programmed with any knowledge concerning that career in my database.
            </template>
        </category>
	</topic>
</aiml>